Guide to the Rome Cheese Manufacturing Association collection, 1863-1951.
Rome Cheese Manufacturing Association collection, 1863-1951.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Rome Cheese Manufacturing Association collection, 1863-1951.
2101
73 pieces.
Articles of incorporation, a stock certificate, accounts, minutes, reports, programs, periodicals, newspaper clippings, a bibliography, and other papers.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Includes a typescript copy of the articles of incorporation (March 1863) of the Association, which succeeded the operation begun by Jesse Williams in 1851; a stock certificate and receipt for a stock subscription payment (2 35 mm. slides, 1863); photostats (1868-1888) of David Williams' accounts with the Rome Cheese Manufacturing Association for making and boxing cheeses, minutes of stockholders' meetings, and treasurer's reports; also programs, periodicals, newspaper clippings, and a bibliography concerning cheese manufacturing, the R.C.M.A. and the Cheese Centennial held in 1951.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Includes a typescript copy of the articles of incorporation (March 1863) of the Association, which succeeded the operation begun by Jesse Williams in 1851; a stock certificate and receipt for a stock subscription payment (2 35 mm. slides, 1863); photostats (1868-1888) of David Williams' accounts with the Rome Cheese Manufacturing Association for making and boxing cheeses, minutes of stockholders' meetings, and treasurer's reports; also programs, periodicals, newspaper clippings, and a bibliography concerning cheese manufacturing, the R.C.M.A. and the Cheese Centennial held in 1951.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Williams, David.; Williams, Jesse, 1798-1864.; Rome Cheese Manufacturing Association.
Subjects:
Cheese factories--New York (State)--Rome.; Cheese industry--New York (State)--Rome.
Places:
Rome (N.Y.)--Economic conditions.; Oneida County (N.Y.)--Economic conditions.
Form and Genre Terms:
Minutes.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- David Williams in account with Rome Cheese Co.
  - July 1868 - boxing cheese, "hogs to whey," etc. (Box 1)
  - Apr. 1870. (Box 1)
  - May-Dec. 1870 - boxing cheese, making, cutting; whey; rennets, lumber, coal, "bandages." (Box 1)
  - June-Aug.; June 1, 1872. (Box 1)
  - Mar.-Dec. 1872. (Box 1)
  - May-Dec. 1874. (Box 1)
  - June-Dec. 1876. (Box 1)
  - May-Nov. 1877. (Box 1)
  - May-Dec. 1880. (Box 1)
- Stockholders of R.C. Mfging Assoc. met on Jan. 12, 1875 and organized trustees appointed - officers elected - notation on reverse side of piece re: withholding report from public, 1877 (penciled copy?). (Box 1)
- Treasurer's Reports
  - July 1885. (Box 1)
  - Aug. 1887 - amount of milk required for a pound of cheese is noted. (Box 1)
  - Apr. 1888. (Box 1)
- Bibliography on cheese mfg. (carbon copy). (Box 1)
- Program for America's Cheese Centennial, 1851- 1951 (three copies). (Box 1)
- Newspaper clippings from Rome Daily Sentinel re: Rome cheese mfg. and centennial, 1922, 1935, 1951 (15 pieces). (Box 1)
- Two issues of The Kraftsman, May-June 1951 and June-July 1951. (Box 1)
- Menlo Park and Edison Institute Museum and Village, Apr. 1961 (unrelated pamphlets). (Box 1)
- Two 35 mm. slides of the following cheese factory items, originals of which are in Rome Historical Society--Fort Stanwix Museum:
  - R.C.M.A. stock certificate, Mar. 1863. (Box 1)
  - Receipt for sum paid on stock subscription; signed by Jesse Williams, Treasurer. (Box 1)
- Typescript carbon copy of articles of association of R.C.M.A., Mar. 23, 1863. (Box 1)
- Photostatic copies (36 pcs.) of the two lead stories on the Williams Cheese Factory, appearing in the Rome Daily Sentinel of June 1, 1951. (Box 1)
- Second Annual Report of the New York State Cheese Manufacturer's Association, with Accompanying Papers, &c., for the Year 1864. Utica, N.Y.: Roberts, 1865. 171 pp. pamphlet (originally in: A.D. White Papers, #1-2-2, Box 241). (Box 1)